<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinking on Fred&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/tags/thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinking on Fred&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/tags/thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Principles of Critical Thinking.</title>
      <link>https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/post/thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/post/thinking/</guid>
      <description>1. A &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo; which can be accept without experiment does not exist. A person can have his own religious belief and values which no need to be proved to be true or not but most of thought and views need to be justified with logical inference and evidence. 2. It is crucial to judge the quality of the evidence. If you are a juror in the court and you need to judge the statements which spoke out by both sides of lawyers measure for measure, at this moment, you cannot directly compare the number of evidence from both sides but evaluate the quality of evidence critically before give the bigger weight to the more faithful evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note of *Justice With Michael Sandel*.</title>
      <link>https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/post/justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haroldwo.github.io/abablog/post/justice/</guid>
      <description>1. Course 1 Consequentialist moral reasoning locates morality in the consequences of an act in the state of the rule that we resolve from the thing you do. Categorical moral reasoning locates morality in certain absolute moral requirements, certain categorical duties and rights, regardless the consequences.
Once the familiar turns strange, it&amp;rsquo;s never quite the same again. Self knowledge is like a lost innocent. However unsettling you find it, you can never be unthought or unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>